Guide to the Olga Rudge Papers Addition
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Printed Material, 1908-1991; Series VIII; 1.67; (4 boxes)
  - Dust jackets and title pages, 1927-65, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 994)
  - Film, 1989 Nov 3 (Box 38, Folder 995)
  - Fondazione Giorgio Cini, 1973-86, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 996)
  - Funeral programs (not E.P.), 1965 (Box 38, Folder 997)
  - Hotel Gritti Palace Lecture Series, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 998)
  - Invitations, 1954-89, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 999)
  - Invitations to E.P.'s funeral, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 1000)
  - Lecture notices, 1983-84 (Box 39, Folder 1001)
  - Micro Mostra Poundiana alla Fondazione Giorgio Cini, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 1002)
  - Pamphlets, 1957-88, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1003-1005)
  - Playbills, 1951-76, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1006)
  - Postcards, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 1007)
  - Postcards, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1008-1009)
  - Posters, 1980-89, n.d.
  - Pound, Ezra: publication announcements, 1908 (Box 40, Folder 1010)
  - Pound, Ezra: funeral announcements, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 1011-1016)
  - Pound, Ezra: funeral announcements, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 1017-1021)
  - Programs and exhibition catalogs, 1912-90, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 1022-1023)
  - Publishers' catalogs, 1957-83, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1024-1025)
  - "Spots and Dots", 1970 (Box 41, Folder 1026)
  - Theater, 1970, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1027)
  - Transcripts from radio, 1954 (Box 41, Folder 1028)
  - Unidentified, 1951-85, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 1029-1030)
- Periodicals, 1917-1990; Series IX; 3.34; (8 boxes)
  Series IX, Periodicals, is arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Abc: Quindicinale di Critica Politica, 1955 Mar 16 (Box 42, Folder 1031)
  - Acque di una storia, 1978 Sep (Box 42, Folder 1032)
  - The Alternative: An American Spectator, 1977 Jan (Box 42, Folder 1033)
  - Ana Eccetera, 1958-69 (Box 42, Folder 1034)
  - Asso di Bastoni: Giornale della Rivoluzione Nazionale Italiana, 1955-56 (Box 42, Folder 1035)
    See also: Oversize, Box 52, folder 1204
  - Atlantic, 1970 Nov (Box 42, Folder 1036)
  - Atlas: a window on the World, 1969 Jan-May (Box 42, Folder 1037)
  - Il Bajocco, 1963 May 12 (Box 42, Folder 1038)
  - Le Belle Arti, 1981 Mar-Apr (Box 42, Folder 1039)
  - Blast, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1040)
  - Il Borghese, 1955-59 (Box 42, Folder 1041-1042)
  - Brain of Pooh, 1969 Jun 21 (Box 42, Folder 1043)
  - Briarcliff Quarterly, 1946 July (Box 42, Folder 1044)
  - Broletto, 1938 Jun (Box 42, Folder 1045)
  - Buffalo Cold Spring Precinct 23 Bulletin, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 1046)
  - Il Caffe': Mensile di attualita, 1954-55, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 1047)
  - Cahiers J: Revue Mensuelle des Jeunesses Artistiques, 1954 Oct (Box 42, Folder 1048)
  - La Citta': Rivista bimestrale di lettere e arti cura di Marcello Pirro, 1964 Oct (Box 42, Folder 1049)
  - El Codega: Settimanale Veneziano di Turismo e Cultura, 1978, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1050)
  - Common Sense, 1970 Oct-Dec (Box 43, Folder 1051)
  - Commonweal, 1955-65 (Box 43, Folder 1052)
  - Connecticut Artists, 1980 (Box 43, Folder 1053)
  - Corriere della Sera, 1955-87
  - Corriere d'Informazione, 1955 Nov (Box 43, Folder 1054)
  - Cronaca di firenze, 1955
    See: Oversize, Box 52, folder 1207
  - Cyril Connolly's One Hundred Modern Books Quarterly, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 1055)
  - Dialogue, 1967 Sep (Box 43, Folder 1056)
  - Dorf Tirol, 1990 Mar 23 (Box 43, Folder 1057)
  - Du: Kulturelle Monatsschrift, 1967 Feb (Box 43, Folder 1058)
  - Elementi: per una rinascita culturale, 1983 Jan-Feb (Box 43, Folder 1059)
  - Encounter, 1969 Apr (Box 43, Folder 1060)
  - Equal Rights: Official Organ of the National Woman's Party, 1949 (Box 43, Folder 1061)
  - L'Espresso, 1979 Jun (Box 43, Folder 1062)
  - L'Europeo, 1955
  - Evening Standard (London), 1951 Apr 3 (Box 43, Folder 1063)
  - Expression, 1958 (Box 43, Folder 1064)
  - Fanatic, 1976 (Box 43, Folder 1065)
  - Fathar For, 1972 Jun (Box 43, Folder 1066)
  - Festival dei Due Mondi [Festival di Spoleto], 1965-79 (Box 44, Folder 1067-1070)
  - La Fiera Letteraria, 1953-73 (Box 44, Folder 1071)
    See also: Oversize, Box 52, folder 1209
  - The Floating Bear, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 1072)
  - Fragen der Freiheit, 1962 Nov (Box 44, Folder 1073)
  - Friendly Local Press, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 1074)
  - Galleria, 1949 (Box 44, Folder 1075)
  - Il Gazzettino, 1977-79 (Box 44, Folder 1076)
  - Il Gazzettino del Caffe, 1971 Mar-Apr (Box 44, Folder 1077)
  - Gente, 1969 Dec 24 (Box 44, Folder 1078)
  - La Giustizia, 1954 Jun (Box 44, Folder 1079)
  - Il Giornale, 1977-81 (Box 44, Folder 1080)
  - Il Giornale d'Italia, 1955 Jul-Aug (Box 45, Folder 1081)
  - Harvard University Gazette, 1974-75 (Box 45, Folder 1082)
  - Herald Review, 1965 Feb-Mar (Box 45, Folder 1083)
  - Idaho's Lampliter, 1952-54 (Box 45, Folder 1084)
  - L'Idea Sociale, 1945 Mar-Apr (Box 45, Folder 1085)
  - L'Illustrazione Italiana, 1958-84 (Box 45, Folder 1086)
  - Incense Oto, 1967 Mar (Box 45, Folder 1087)
  - Incontra di Poeti, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 1088)
  - Intrepid, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 1089)
  - Itinerario, 1966 Nov-Dec (Box 45, Folder 1090)
  - La Lettura del Medico, 1964 Sep (Box 45, Folder 1091)
  - Letture, 1987 Oct (Box 45, Folder 1092)
  - The Listener, 1960-64 (Box 45, Folder 1093)
  - Luceafarul, 1969 Jan (Box 45, Folder 1094)
  - London Times: The Sunday Times Magazine, 1972 (Box 45, Folder 1095)
  - Malebolge, 1964 (Box 45, Folder 1096)
  - Man's Magazine, 1960 Apr (Box 45, Folder 1097)
  - Mark Twain Journal, 1962-68 (Box 46, Folder 1098)
  - Il Mare: Giornale del Tigullio, 1954 Oct-Nov (Box 46, Folder 1099)
  - La Martinella di Milano, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 1100)
  - Meridiano di Roma, 1917 (Box 46, Folder 1101)
  - Il Messaggero, 1954 Jul 19 (Box 46, Folder 1102)
  - Il Mondo, 1954-56 (Box 46, Folder 1103)
    See also: Oversize, Box 52, folder 1210
  - Il Nazionale, 1954-58 (Box 46, Folder 1104)
    See also: Oversize, Box 52, folders 1211-1213
  - Niagara Frontier Review, 1966 (Box 46, Folder 1105)
  - New Blackfriars, 1964 Nov (Box 46, Folder 1106)
  - The New English Weekly, 1948 Oct 7 (Box 46, Folder 1107)
  - New Haven Register, 1951 May 29 (Box 46, Folder 1108)
  - New Nation, 1964 Dec (Box 46, Folder 1109)
  - The New Times, 1955 Oct 21 (Box 46, Folder 1110)
  - Noose, 1969-70 (Box 46, Folder 1111)
  - Notiziaro di San Giorgio, 1974 Apr-Oct (Box 46, Folder 1112)
  - Notizie dalla Fondazione Giorgio Cini, 1977-81 (Box 46, Folder 1113)
  - Le Nouvel Observateur, 1974 Dec (Box 46, Folder 1114)
  - Nuova Rivista Europea, 1983 Jan (Box 46, Folder 1115)
  - Nuova Solidarieta, 1985 Apr (Box 46, Folder 1116)
  - Nuovistudi Gentiliani, 1966 Dec (Box 46, Folder 1117)
  - Nuovo Meridiano, 1985 Oct-Nov (Box 46, Folder 1118)
  - Oggi, 1954 Apr 8 (Box 46, Folder 1119)
  - Ophir, 1968 Feb (Box 47, Folder 1120)
  - Paese Sera: Ultimissima della notte, 1954 Jun (Box 47, Folder 1121)
  - Panorama delle Arti, 1971 May (Box 47, Folder 1122)
  - Parsifal, 1985 Sep-Oct (Box 47, Folder 1123)
  - Le Peintre: Guide du Collectionneur, 1966 Mar (Box 47, Folder 1124)
  - Pennsylvania Gazette, 1973 Feb (Box 47, Folder 1125)
  - Playmen, 1967 Oct (Box 47, Folder 1126)
  - Plural, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 1127)
  - Poetry Flash, 1985 Nov (Box 47, Folder 1128)
  - Poetry Newsletter, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 1129)
  - Poetry Pilot, 1973 Jan (Box 47, Folder 1130)
  - Primavera Missionaria, 1983 Apr (Box 47, Folder 1131)
  - La Quinzaine litteraire, 1966-67 (Box 47, Folder 1132)
  - Rapallo, 1963-64 (Box 47, Folder 1133)
  - The Reporter, 1954 Feb 2 (Box 47, Folder 1134)
  - La Repubblica, 1989 Jun (Box 47, Folder 1135)
  - Il Resto del Carlino, 1955
  - Rivarol, 1956 Jan 26
    See: Oversize, Box 53, folder 1216
  - Rome Daily American, 1954 Jun 17 (Box 47, Folder 1136)
  - Santa Fe New Mexican, 1935 Mar-Nov (Box 47, Folder 1137)
  - The Scotsman, 1935 Jun 10 (Box 47, Folder 1138)
  - Il Secolo d'Italia, 1953-85 (Box 47, Folder 1139-1140)
    See also: Oversize, Box 53, folders 1217-1218
  - Segnacolo, 1965 Sep-Oct (Box 47, Folder 1141)
  - Siena Cronache, 1967 Aug 17 (Box 47, Folder 1142)
  - Signals, 1964-65 (Box 48, Folder 1143)
  - Simplicissimus, 1940-44 (Box 48, Folder 1144)
  - The Social Crediter, 1939-40 (Box 48, Folder 1145)
  - Social Justice, 1937-42 (Box 48, Folder 1146)
  - Social Progress, 1957 Mar 8 (Box 48, Folder 1147)
  - Il Sole, 1944 May 27 (Box 48, Folder 1148)
  - Il Sole Che Sorge, 1945 May 20 (Box 48, Folder 1149)
  - La Stampa, 1931-89 (Box 48, Folder 1150-1151)
  - Suddeutsche Zeitung Magazin, 1991 Nov 11 (Box 48, Folder 1152)
  - Svegliatevi!, 1987 Aug 8 (Box 48, Folder 1153)
  - Die Tat, 1953 Nov 7 (Box 48, Folder 1154)
  - Task Force, 1965 Aug-Sep (Box 48, Folder 1155)
  - The TeleVort, 1977-81 (Box 48, Folder 1156)
  - Tematy, 1964 (Box 48, Folder 1157)
  - Tempo, 1976 Apr 11 (Box 48, Folder 1158)
  - Il Tempo, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 1159)
    See also: Oversize, Box 53, folder 1219
  - Terra di Siena, 1947-51 (Box 49, Folder 1160)
  - Text and Kritik, 1965 Oct (Box 49, Folder 1161)
  - Tigullio Bacherontius, 1982 May (Box 49, Folder 1162)
  - Time, 1965-86 (Box 49, Folder 1163)
  - The Times Literary Supplement, 1969-81 (Box 49, Folder 1164)
  - TOOL: Quaderni di Scrittura simbiotica, 1965 (Box 49, Folder 1165)
  - Undercurrent, 1969 Aug 20 (Box 49, Folder 1166)
  - University of Tulsa Alumni Magazine, 1967 (Box 49, Folder 1167)
  - Unmuzzled Ox Magazine, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 1168)
  - Vigil, 1955-58 (Box 49, Folder 1169)
  - de Volkskrant, 1989 Jun 3 (Box 49, Folder 1170)
  - Welt und Wort, 1968 Oct 23 (Box 49, Folder 1171)
  - Die Weltwoche, 1954 Jan 15 (Box 49, Folder 1172)
  - Words: The New Literary Forum, 1985 Oct (Box 49, Folder 1173)
  - Yale Literary Magazine, 1955 May (Box 49, Folder 1174)
  - Yale Poetry Review, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 1175)
  - Zeit Magazin, 1987 Sep 18 (Box 49, Folder 1176)
  - Zeta, 1976 Aug (Box 49, Folder 1177)
- Audiotapes and Other Recordings, 1967-1985; Series X; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series X, Audiotapes and Other Recordings, is organized into two subseries. Audiotapes are arranged alphabetically by title of tape as given on original storage boxes.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 50 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Audiotape Reels and Audiocassettes
    - Basil Bunting reading "Briggflatts" at Harvard, 1967 Mar 27; 1; 01:14:51; Static and a high amount of hiss and background noise can be heard on the audiotape reel. (Box 50, Item barcode 39002091243114)
    - Ezra Pound, Cantos I-V, translated into Italian and read by Mary de Rachewiltz-Pound, undated; 1; 00:21:26; A high amount of hum can be heard on the audiotape reel. (Box 50, Item barcode 39002091243122)
    - "The Letters of Ezra Pound and Harriet Monroe", 1973 February; 1; 00:45:27; Static and a buzz can be heard on this audiotape reel. Low levels of audio recorded on original from 31:40-35:50. (Box 50, Item barcode 39002091243130)
      Recorded at Thorne Hall, Northwestern University, when presented in honor of Poetry Magazine's 60th Anniversary. A script for the open and close of this audiotape is included. It details the actors involved in the readings and mentions poems from various writers that are also included.
    - "Lumina-David Blake" from the Cantos of Ezra Pound, 1970 April; 1; 01:08:48 (Box 50, Item barcode 39002091243148)
    - Noguchi, Pound, Rudge, Fuller meeting at the Cini Foundation, Venice, Italy, 1985 October; 1; 00:25:53; Static and high background noise can be heard on the cassette. The program is distorted at times. (Box 50, Item barcode 39002091243163)
    - "Pound Symposium", Belfast, 1973 March 21; 1; 01:19:42; Static and a high amount of buzz can be heard on the audiotape. (Box 50, Item barcode 39002091243155)
      Included on the audiotape reel are Chairman Hugh McDiarmid, Singh, Donoghue, Bauman, Edwards.
    - Songs of Ezra Pound - Walter Morse Rummel, "Nine Troubador Songs", Reel I, undated; 1; 00:18:44 (Box 50, Item barcode 39002091243189)
    - Songs of Ezra Pound - Walter Morse Rummel, "Nine Troubador Songs", Reel II, undated; 1; 00:16:52 (Box 50, Item barcode 39002091243171)
  - Sound Discs
    - "Ezra Pound: Fragmente aus den Cantos XVII, XXV, XXVI," Erker Verlag, St. Gallen (Box 50, Folder 1185)
- Oversize, 3.65; (3 boxes)
  - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1186)
  - "Diploma di Collaborazione", 1957 (Box 51, Folder 1187)
  - Newspapers collected by Peter Buchanan Templeton, 1849-85 (Box 51, Folder 1188-1194)
  - Rudge, Olga, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1195)
  - Places: Unidentified, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1196)
  - Pound, Ezra: galley proof of "Cavalcanti" (Box bsd, folder 1197)
  - Pound, Ezra: galley proof of Cantos XVII-XIX (Box bsd, folder 1198)
  - Sitwell, Edith: galley proof of "Ezra Pound" (Box bsd, folder 1199)
  - Artwork (Annotated by Olga Rudge), 1959, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1200-1201)
  - Posters, 1973-1983, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1202-1203)
  - Asso di bastoni, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 1204)
  - Corriere della Serra, 1955-87 (Box 52, Folder 1205-1206)
  - Cronaca di firenze, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 1207)
  - L'Europeo, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 1208)
  - La Fiera Litteraria, 1955 (Box 52, Folder 1209)
  - Il Mondo, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 1210)
  - Il Nazionale, 1955-56 (Box 52, Folder 1211-1213)
  - Il Resto di Carlino, 1955 (Box 53, Folder 1214-1215)
  - Rivarol, 1956 (Box 53, Folder 1216)
  - Il Secolo d'Italia, 1955 (Box 53, Folder 1217-1218)
  - Tempo, 1955 (Box 53, Folder 1219)